netweather.tv 2019-11-04

# Privacy Policy - Netweather

#### Who We Are

**MBC Netweather Ltd** (Netweather) gather and process your personal information in accordance with this privacy notice and in compliance with the relevant data protection Regulation and laws. This notice provides you with the necessary information regarding your rights and our obligations, and explains how, why and when we process your personal data.

Our registered office is at 3rd Floor, 86-90 Paul Street, London, EC2A 4NE and we are a company registered in England and Wales under company number 07063403.

**Our services:** When we refer to our services, they are a combination of our website (Netweather.tv), our apps, our API and data-feeds and any other related products that we offer.

#### Information That We Collect

Netweather processes your personal information to meet our legal, statutory and contractual obligations and to provide you with our products and services. We will never collect any unnecessary personal data from you and do not process your information in any way, other than as specified in this notice.

#### Cookies (and other browser or device based storage)

We set and use (first party) cookies on Netweather for a number of purposes - these ensure a good experience and have functions which include keeping you logged in to any parts of the site you may be registered for (such as the forum or Netweather Extra), storing settings and forecast locations for your use as you move around the site or for return visits, and for us to analyse anonymised usage statistics and data for the usage of our website and apps.

Our first party cookies contain no personal information, and are set solely to be used on Netweather. You can control how websites use cookies through your browser settings, but please be aware that parts of Netweather may not function correctly should you choose to block all cookies set by the site.

Our service partners, such as Cloudflare and Google Cloud also set cookies to provide functionality and security for our services - these don't contain personal information.

Our advertising partners may also store and process 3rd party cookies, these are primarily used to provide relevant advertising to you, but are only used if you have given consent. 

#### Web server logs

Similar to the vast majority of websites, our servers also make logs of the usage of our website and services (such as our apps and data feed API’s). These log files include information such as IP address, browser and device type, pages visited and the urls of referring pages.

We store these logs securely and use them to track any errors, for security auditing, and to identify or investigate any potentially malicious use of our services. We regularly ‘rotate’ these logs and they are usually not kept for longer than 30 days. We won’t share log files with any third parties, unless required to by law, or if they’re required to establish or exercise our legal rights (eg to defend against legal claims). We may also anonymise them (by removing any IP addresses) and share them with our service providers should they be required for troubleshooting or investigation.

#### Registering for parts of our website or communicating with us

When registering on some of our services or communicating with us via our website or apps (for example registering for our community forums, MessageCentre, Netweather Extra, entering any competitions or promotions we run, or contacting our support desk), we may ask for, and should you choose to share it with us, collect relevant personal information from you.

These may typically include:

  * Name
  * Personal or Business Email
  * Address
  * Telephone number

Through the process of your registration for any of our services or contact with us, we may use your personal details to contact you (for instance to reply to a support ticket, or confirm your registration, or remind you when a subscription is about to end), and this contact will be in accordance with applicable law.

If purchasing one of our paid-for products (for example, a Netweather Extra subscription), we may also ask you for: 

  * Payment details (although we do not store any payment information, we simply pass those details securely to our payment provider, Stripe)
  * Billing address

#### How We Use Your Personal Data (Our Legal Basis for Processing)

Netweather takes your privacy very seriously and will never disclose, share or sell your data without your consent; unless required to do so by law. We only retain your data for as long as is necessary and for the purpose(s) specified in this notice. The purposes and reasons for processing your personal data are detailed below:

  * To enable you to access and use our website along with any associated services, as well as to provide, maintain and promote them.
  * To process your registrations and transactions including sending you confirmations of them.
  * To send informational and transactional messages to you about any services or features you have registered for, or to answer your requests and questions, send reminders or other relevant notices.
  * To send informational or commercial communications if you have consented or subscribed to them.
  * To analyse trends and usage of our website.
  * To comply with any legal obligation and to investigate any malicious, fraudulent or illegal use or access of our website, apps and other services.
  * To personalise our services and web pages.
  * To send mobile notifications to you via our apps or browser notifications to you via our website.
  * To show you relevant advertising on our website or apps.

Where we rely on your consent to process your personal data, you may decline or withdraw that consent at any time. We may also use our legitimate interest to process your personal data, and in this instance you have the right to object.

#### Your Rights

You have the right to access any personal information that Netweather processes about you and to request information about:

  * What personal data we hold about you
  * The purposes of the processing
  * The categories of personal data concerned
  * The recipients to whom the personal data has/will be disclosed
  * How long we intend to store your personal data for
  * If we did not collect the data directly from you, information about the source

If you believe that we hold any incomplete or inaccurate data about you, you have the right to ask us to correct and/or complete the information and we will strive to do so as quickly as possible; unless there is a valid reason for not doing so, at which point you will be notified.

You also have the right to request erasure of your personal data or to restrict processing (where applicable) in accordance with the data protection laws; as well as to object to any direct marketing from us. Where applicable, you have the right to data portability of your information and the right to be informed about any automated decision-making we may use. If we receive a request from you to exercise any of the above rights, we may ask you to verify your identity before acting on the request; this is to ensure that your data is protected and kept secure.

Please [email us](https://www.netweather.tv/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#44302125296a3032) should you have any requests in relation to the above, including the removal of any personal information you may have publicly posted on our community forums. We will respond to you as quickly as possible and always within 28 days.

#### Sharing and Disclosing Your Personal Information

We do not share or disclose any of your personal information without your consent, other than for the purposes specified in this notice or where there is a legal requirement.

MBC Netweather uses the third-parties listed below to help in the running of our business by providing services and business functions; however, all processors acting on our behalf only process your data in accordance with instructions from us and comply fully with this privacy notice, data protection laws and any other appropriate confidentiality and security measures.

##### Stripe Payments UK Ltd

We use Stripe as a payments processor for our Netweather Extra subscriptions and any other paid for products we offer. They are authorised by the FCA to provide payment services and have all the relevant data protection and security measures in place. You can read their privacy policy here: [Stripe Privacy Policy](https://stripe.com/gb/privacy).

##### Paypal Europe

We also use Paypal as a payments processor for Netweather Extra subscriptions and other paid for products. Like Stripe, they are authorised by the FCA to provide payment services and have all the relevant data protection and security measures in place. Their privacy policy is here: [PayPal Privacy Policy](https://www.paypal.com/uk/webapps/mpp/ua/privacy-full).

##### Google Cloud

We use the Google cloud as our server hosting provider. The datacentres we use for our servers and data storage are in the EU. You can view their security and privacy information here: [Google Cloud Privacy Policy](https://cloud.google.com/security/privacy/)

##### Cloudflare

Cloudflare are a leading web performance and security company who we use for our website and apps, like us, they log web traffic going through their servers. Their privacy policy is here: [Cloudflare Privacy Policy](https://www.cloudflare.com/privacypolicy/).

##### Amazon Cloud Services EU

We use the Amazon SES (Simple Email Service) to send email for our website and associated services. View their privacy policy here: [Amazon cloud privacy policy](https://aws.amazon.com/compliance/data-privacy-faq/).

##### Zendesk

Zendesk provide us with our help/support desk software, so they process your contact details when you contact us for support. Their privacy policy is here: [Zendesk privacy policy](https://www.zendesk.co.uk/company/customers-partners/eu-data-protection/).

##### JWplayer

Jwplayer provide us with our video players and video hosting, they set cookies to track usage of the players. Their privacy policy is here: [JWplayer privacy policy](https://www.jwplayer.com/privacy-updated/).

##### Advertising partners

Our advertising partners provide advertising on our website and apps and enable us to provide a lot of our services for free. With your consent they use cookies to provide more relevant and hopefully interesting ads. Please see our [privacy manager](https://www.netweather.tv/#) to check your consent settings. You can also visit the [NAI website](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/) for more info and to opt-out of tailored online ads.

As well as the service providers and reasons listed above, we may also share your data for the reasons shown below:

  * Where we believe, in good faith, that sharing particular data is required to prevent illegal activities, including threats to harm any individual.
  * To comply with any legal obligations we may have.
  * In the event of a sale or merger of our business.

#### Safeguarding Measures

Netweather takes your privacy seriously and takes every reasonable measure and precaution to protect and secure your personal data. We work hard to protect you and your information from unauthorised access, alteration, disclosure or destruction and have several layers of security measures in place, including:

  * SSL
  * Encryption of data at rest and in transit
  * Pseudonymisation of data
  * Authentication policies
  * Firewall
  * Cloudflare security
  * Regular security updates

#### Transfers Outside the EU

Netweather may, at times, utilise some products or services (or parts of them) that may be hosted/stored in the USA, which means that we may transfer any information which is submitted by you through the website outside the European Economic Area ("EEA").

Therefore, when you use our services, any personal information you submit may be stored on servers which are hosted in outside of the EEA. Where this is the case, these providers use the necessary level of protection for your information, and, if storing data in the USA are signed up to the EU-US privacy shield, and abide by strict agreements and measures to protect your data and comply with the relevant data protection laws.

#### Consequences of Not Providing Your Data

You are not obligated to provide your personal information to Netweather, however, as this information is required to provide you with some of our services, we will not be able to offer those services without it.

#### Legitimate Interests

As noted in the ‘How We Use Your Personal Data’ section of this notice, we occasionally process your personal information under the legitimate interests’ legal basis. Where this is the case, we have carried out a thorough Legitimate Interests’ Assessment (LIA) to ensure that we have weighed your interests and any risk posed to you against our own interests; ensuring that they are proportionate and appropriate.

Examples of this may include:

  * Personalising our website, services and communication
  * Communicating relevant, service related information
  * Fraud identification and protection
  * To analyse and better understand the usage of our website and services
  * To improve our services
  * To measure the effectiveness of our marketing

You have the right to object to our processing your data in this way, should you wish to do so, please [email us](https://www.netweather.tv/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#daaebfbbb7f4aeac)

#### How Long We Keep Your Data

Netweather only ever retains personal information for as long as is necessary and we have strict review and retention policies in place to meet these obligations. Where you have consented to us using your details for communication with you (such as the MessageCentre), we will keep such data until you notify us otherwise and/or withdraw your consent.

#### Lodging A Complaint

Netweather only processes your personal information in compliance with this privacy notice and in accordance with the relevant data protection laws. If, however you wish to raise a complaint regarding the processing of your personal data or are unsatisfied with how we have handled your information, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the ICO.
